First Casualty Press Records
© 2002 University of Connecticut
First Casualty Press Records.
1960-1981.
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center.
Paquet, Basil T.
7.84 linear feet.
Vietnam War veteran Basil T. Paquet founded First Casualty Press in September 1971 with fellow veterans Larry Rottmann and Jan Barry Crumb. Paquet both edited and contributed to Winning Hearts and Minds: War Poems by Vietnam Veterans and Free Fire Zone: Short Stories by Vietnam Veterans. Paquet won the Wallace Stevens Award for Poetry in 1969.
MSS19730001
History
Vietnam War veteran Basil T. Paquet founded First Casualty Press in September 1971 with fellow veterans Larry Rottmann and Jan Barry Crumb. Paquet both edited and contributed to Winning Hearts and Minds: War Poems by Vietnam Veterans and Free Fire Zone: Short Stories by Vietnam Veterans. Paquet won the Wallace Stevens Award for Poetry in 1969.
Scope and Content
The collection consists primarily of poetry and fiction written by Vietnam War veterans reflecting on their war experiences, submitted to First Casualty Press for consideration for publication. The collection also contains correspondence between First Casualty Press and authors, publishers, readers, and war veterans and materials related to the publication process, such as typescripts, proofs, promotional materials and reviews. Published books and periodicals were removed from this collection and placed in the Archives & Special Collections general collection. The bulk of the collection dates from 1970 to 1973. Of note are letters from Coretta Scott King and Senator George McGovern applauding First Casualty Press for their work in the anti-war movement. Due to the subject matter of this collection, some materials illustrate and/or describe extremely graphic violence.
Organization
Series I: Correspondence (1969-1981).
Series II: Writings (1960-1978).
Series III: Photographs and Drawing (undated).
Related Material
Archives & Special Collections has a substantial collection of small literary press and alternative press materials. For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the reference desk.
Arrangement
The materials have been refoldered and subdivided for easy access. Correspondence is subdivided into author correspondence and general correspondence. Writings are subdivided according to publication: Winning Hearts and Minds, Free Fire Zone, and Post-Mortem. Writings also include general submissions by authors that were never published and papers related to press business. Photographs and drawing are arranged alphabetically by name of the photographer/artist.
Separated Material
The following materials have been removed from the collection and catalogued.
Books
Committee of Small Magazine Editors and Publishers. Cosmep Bookstore Survey, COSMEP, 1971.
Committee of Small Magazine Editors and Publishers. The Small Publisher's Book, COSMEP, 1972.
DeLuca, Angelo. Legacy of Life: Ariel and Frankenstein Come to Grips, Western World Press, 1972.
Henderson, Bill, ed. The Publish-It-Yourself Handbook, Yonkers, NY: Pushcart Book Press, 1973.
[Chapter about First Casualty Press, p.139-142]
Kushner, [Steam Smoke?]. Lifesavers, Hillside, NJ: Mont Sainte Victoire, 1972. WPS 3652
Livingstone, Richard. Vietnam Verses...Speak in Shame and Sorrow, Movement Labor New England Free Press, 1970.
Martin, Earl E. A Poet Goes to War, Bozeman, MT: Big Sky Books, 1970.
McKeown, Tom. The Cloud Keeper, Dublin: Seafront Press, 1972.
Paquet, Basil T., Wayne Karlin and Larry Rottmann. Free Fire Zone: Short Stories by Vietnam Veterans, Coventry, CT: First Casualty Press Fund, 1973.
A 4587, A 4588
Paquet, Basil T., Wayne Karlin and Larry Rottmann. Free Fire Zone: Short Stories by Vietnam Veterans, New York, NY: McGraw-Hill Paperbacks, 1973.
A 4589
Paquet, Basil T., Jan Barry and Larry Rottmann. Winning Hearts and Minds: War Poems by Vietnam Veterans, Brooklyn, NY: First Casualty Press, 1972.
Paquet, Basil T., Jan Barry and Larry Rottmann. Winning Hearts and Minds: War Poems by Vietnam Veterans, 2nd edition, Brooklyn, NY: First Casualty Press, 1972.
Paquet, Basil T., Jan Barry and Larry Rottmann. Winning Hearts and Minds: War Poems by Vietnam Veterans, New York, NY: McGraw-Hill, 1972.
Taylor, John. 21 Poems, Portland, OR: Tree Frog, 1972. WPS 3653
Whitaker, T. J. The Empty Road, T.J. Whitaker, 1971.
Periodicals
Ark River Review, poems by Danny Rendleman, p.6-7 1972.
Aspect, review, p.25-28, Oct./Nov. 1972.
College English, review & poem re-prints, p.1022-1026, Apr. 1973.
Commentaries, advertisement, p.20, Spring 1973.
Entertainment Gallery, review, p.28, Mar. 1973.
Fervent Valley, poems by Fielding Dawson, Spring 1972.
Freedomways, poem re-prints, p.217-221, Summer 1972.
Friends Journal, review, p.388, July 1/15, 1972.
Friends Journal, review, p.334, June 1/15, 1973.
Glamour, article, p.123, Dec. 1972.
Liberation News Service (LNS) [oversized] 538, 539, July 11, 14, 1973.
Long Island Review, review, p.30-33, Winter 1973.
Midwest Quarterly, review, p.455-456, Summer 1972.
New Republic, review, p.33, May 27, 1972.
New Republic, War Hero by Ward Just (Clyde Reeves), Jul. 21, 1973.
Occum Ridge Review, advertisement, p.393, Spring/Summer 197.
Progressive, advertisement, p.39, Aug. 1972.
Progressive, advertisement, p.53, Sept. 1972.
Progressive, VVAW letter to CBS, p.49, May 1973.
Scholastic Voice, poem re-print, p.2, Feb. 26, 1973.
Science for the People, review, p.14-15, Nov. 1972.
Scope, poem re-prints, p.4-11, Mar. 12, 1973.
Saturday Review, VVAW article, p.7-26, Oct. 1972.
Saturday Review, interview with poet Mike McCusker, p.61, Dec. 1972.
Student Lawyer, poem re-prints, p.44-48, Sept. 1972.
Sundance, review, p.87, Aug.-Sept. 1972.
West Coast Review, advertisement, p.89, Jan. 1973.
Index Terms
This record series is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Persons:
Rottmann, Larry, 1942- .; Karlin, Wayne.; Paquet, Basil T., 1944- .; Barry, Jan, 1943- .
Places:
Connecticut--Business, industries and trades--Publishing.; Coventry (Conn.)--Business, industries, and trades--Publishing.; Connecticut--Cultural affairs--Literature.; Coventry (Conn.)--Cultural affairs--Literature.
Subjects:
Editors--United States.; Veterans' writings, American; Publishers and publishing--Connecticut.; Authors and publishers--United States.; American poetry--20th century.; Small presses--Connecticut.; Vietnamese Conflict, 1961-1975--Poetry.; Short stories, American.; Vietnamese Conflict, 1961-1975--Fiction.
Document Types:
Correspondence.; Publications.; Photographs.; Administrative Records.; Press releases.; Fliers. [printed matter]; Manuscripts.; Galley proofs.; Typescripts.; Photocopies.; Books.; Drawings.; Posters.; Anthologies.; Fiction.; Poems.; Reviews (Criticism).
Occupations:
Author.; Editor.
Restrictions on Access
There are no access restrictions on this collection.
Acquisition Information
The collection was purchased in 1973.
Detailed Description
- Series I: Correspondence, 1969-1981
  - Author Correspondence
    - Abbott, Gregory L., undated, 1973 (Box 1:1)
    - Adams, Bill, 1971 Jan 22 (Box 1:2)
    - Aitken, James (Jim), undated, 1973 Jan-Feb (Box 1:3)
    - Allen, Bert, undated (Box 1:4)
    - Anderson, Robert L., undated, 1972, 1974 (Box 1:5)
    - Apple, Lynn N., undated, 1972-1973 (Box 1:6)
    - Baber, Asia, 1972-1973 (Box 1:7)
    - Barry, Jan, undated, 1971-1973 (Box 1:8)
    - Bartling, Peter R., undated (Box 1:9)
    - Bayless, David, undated, 1972-1973 (Box 1:10)
    - Beattie, Paul (Erhma), 1972 Aug 18 (Box 1:11)
    - Berenbak, Peter, undated, 1973 Jul 10 (Box 1:12)
    - Berry, D.C., 1973-1975 (Box 1:13)
    - Bittle, Camilla, 1972 Sep 5 (Box 1:14)
    - Blanchette, Patricia, 1972-1973 (Box 1:15)
    - Bobrowsky, Igor, undated, 1971-1973 (Box 1:16)
    - Bodey, Donald L., 1973-1974 (Box 1:17)
    - Boggis, Jay, undated, 1973 Aug (Box 1:18)
    - Borden, Robert H., 1971-1972 (Box 1:19)
    - Boyer, Dennis L., 1973, 1976 (Box 1:20)
    - Boyer, James, 1971-1973 (Box 1:21)
    - Bradley, Douglas J., 1973 Feb (Box 1:22)
    - Bravar, Stephen M., undated (Box 1:23)
    - Bronder, Howard George, undated, 1973 (Box 1:24)
    - Brown, Steven E., 1973 Jun 6 (Box 1:25)
    - Brownstein, Stanley, 1971-1973 (Box 1:26)
    - Bruno, Anthony, 1972-1973 (Box 1:27)
    - Burnson, Laurie, undated (Box 1:28)
    - Bush, Ronald A., undated (Box 1:29)
    - Buster, Robert D., undated, 1971-1973 (Box 1:30)
    - Casey, Michael, undated, 1972-1974 (Box 1:31)
    - Chianelli, John P., Jr., 1973 (Box 1:32)
    - Childs, Geoffrey S., undated, 1973 Aug (Box 1:33)
    - Clinton, L. De Witt, undated, 1972-1973 (Box 1:34)
    - Clodfelter, Mike, undated (Box 1:35)
    - Cole, Lawrence, undated, 1969-1973 (Box 1:36)
    - Coleman, Horace, 1972 Aug 28 (Box 1:37)
    - Cote, Raymond W., undated (Box 1:38)
    - Cram, Robert, undated (Box 1:39)
    - Crawford, Jack, undated (Box 1:40)
    - Cross, Frank A., Jr., undated, 1971-1973 (Box 1:41)
    - Culhane, Claire, 1973 Feb-Mar (Box 1:42)
    - Currer, William J. (Barney), 1971-1973 (Box 1:43)
    - Davis, George, undated, 1972-1973 (Box 1:44)
    - Dawson, Fielding, undated, 1972 Oct 9 (Box 1:45)
    - Deskin, William C., Sr. (Skip), undated, 1973-1974 (Box 1:46)
    - Dewey, Al, 1972 Oct-Nov (Box 1:47)
    - Dietz, Frederick W., Jr., 1973-1974 (Box 1:48)
    - DiZazzo, Raymond, 1973-1974 (Box 1:49)
    - Dorris, James R., undated, 1972-1973 (Box 1:50)
    - Douglass, Richard N., 1972-1973 (Box 1:51)
    - Downey, Mark, undated, 1971-1974 (Box 1:52)
    - Driscoll, Gregory V., 1973 Apr, Aug (Box 1:53)
    - Duncan, Angus, undated, 1972 Dec 1 (Box 1:54)
    - Earl-Clark, David, 1972 Nov 26 (Box 1:55)
    - Egendorf, Arthur, 1972-1973 (Box 1:56)
    - Ehrhart, William D., undated, 1971-1973 (Box 1:57)
    - Ellis, R. Joseph, 1973 May, Aug (Box 1:58)
    - Emeny, Mary, undated, 1972-1973 (Box 1:59)
    - Ettenson, Paul, 1972 Aug, Oct (Box 1:60)
    - Fegho, John A., 1972 Aug-Sep (Box 1:61)
    - Flanagan, Jim, 1973 May 29 (Box 1:62)
    - Flynn, Daniel, 1973 Feb 8 (Box 1:63)
    - Flynn, Michael, 1973-1974 (Box 1:64)
    - Forman, William H., Jr, 1972 May 26 (Box 1:65)
    - Fries, Larry K., 1971-1973 (Box 1:66)
    - Fritzinger, Dennis, undated, 1973 Aug 14 (Box 1:67)
    - Funge, Robert, undated, 1972-1973 (Box 1:68)
    - Goldhammer, Art, Apr 6 (Box 1:69)
    - Goldstein, Harvey, 1972 Sep 25 (Box 1:70)
    - Gott, George, 1973, 1975 (Box 1:71)
    - Gottlieb, Ed, 1973 Aug 16 (Box 1:72)
    - Grajewski, Julian, undated, 1972-1973 (Box 1:73)
    - Gray, Amlin, 1972 Oct 2 (Box 1:74)
    - Greenwood, Bruce Walton, undated, 1973 (Box 1:75)
    - Griffin, Tom, undated, 1973 Jul-Aug (Box 2:76)
    - Grothus, Edward B., 1972 Nov 21 (Box 2:77)
    - Hahn, Robert C., undated, 1971-1973 (Box 2:78)
    - Hall, Ralph E., undated, 1973 Jul 25 (Box 2:79)
    - Halpern, Sue, undated, 1972-1973 (Box 2:80)
    - Halvorsen, S., 1973 Jun 18 (Box 2:81)
    - Hardin, E.R., III (Buzz), 1973 Jan-Feb (Box 2:82)
    - Harris, James Frances, 1973 Apr 30 (Box 2:83)
    - Hasford, Gustav, undated, 1972-1973 (Box 2:84)
    - Hassett, Steve, undated, 1972-1973 (Box 2:85)
    - Hatch, Stephen R., undated, 1972-1973 (Box 2:86)
    - Hathaway, W. Stephen, undated, 1972-1974 (Box 2:87)
    - Heinrichs, Ken, 1972 (Box 2:88)
    - Helman, B.F., 1972 May 13 (Box 2:89)
    - Henry, Lynn, 1972 May, Nov (Box 2:90)
    - Holloway, Frederic Lord, 1968-1969 (Box 2:91)
    - Hounshell, William, undated, 1973 Aug-Oct (Box 2:92)
    - Hudak, Edward J., 1972-1974undated (Box 2:93)
    - Huddle, David, undated, 1972-1973 (Box 2:94)
    - Hulley, James J., 1972 Nov 27 (Box 2:95)
    - Hunt, Robert M., 1972 Nov 9 (Box 2:96)
    - Jackson, Daniel B., 1973 Jul 25 (Box 2:97)
    - Jackson, John, undated (Box 2:98)
    - Jacobson, Philip, undated, 1973 (Box 2:99)
    - Johnson, Michael F., 1973 Apr 26 (Box 2:100)
    - Johnson, Michael H., 1973 Mar, Aug (Box 2:101)
    - Karlin, Wayne, undated, 1972 Jul (Box 2:102)
    - Kemp, Donald G., undated, 1973 Aug 16 (Box 2:103)
    - Kimpel, John M., 1972-1973, 1975 (Box 2:104)
    - King, Peter B., undated (Box 2:105)
    - Knaster, Julian, 1971-1973 (Box 2:106)
    - Kohler, Harrison, undated, 1970-1973, 1975 (Box 2:107)
    - Kramer, Larry, 1973 Jul, Aug (Box 2:108)
    - Krohn, Herbert, undated, 1972-1973 (Box 2:109)
    - Lackman, Carol, undated (Box 2:110)
    - Lanzek, James, 1973 Jul 22 (Box 2:111)
    - Leinsdorf, Joshua, 1972 Jun Nov (Box 2:112)
    - Lerner, Charles Philip, 1969, 1972 (Box 2:113)
    - Levy, Marc S., undated, 1972-1973 (Box 2:114)
    - Lewallen, John, undated, 1972 Sep, Nov (Box 2:115)
    - Licciardi, Richard, undated (Box 2:116)
    - Little, Loyd, 1972-1973 (Box 2:117)
    - Livingston, Gordon S., 1971-1972 (Box 2:118)
    - Livingston, Richard, undated (Box 2:119)
    - Lucas, Peter B., 1972-1973 (Box 2:120)
    - Lupo, Robert E., undated, 1971-1973 (Box 2:121)
    - Lytle, John, 1971-1973 (Box 2:122)
    - Madden, William M., 1973 Feb 12 (Box 2:123)
    - Mann, Polly, 1972 Sep, Nov (Box 2:124)
    - Martin, Earl, 1973 Jun, Feb (Box 2:125)
    - Martin-Trigona, Anthony R., 1972-1973 (Box 2:126)
    - Maxham, Jerry, 1973-1974 (Box 2:127)
    - McClelland, Barry R., 1973 Jan 24 (Box 2:128)
    - McCormack, Allen E., undated, 1972 May, Oct (Box 2:129)
    - McCusker, Michael (Mike), undated, 1972-1973 (Box 2:130)
    - McGarry, Thomas, 1972 Sep, Nov (Box 2:131)
    - McGuiness, Daniel M., 1972-1973 (Box 2:132)
    - McLain, Jack, undated, 1971-1973 (Box 2:133)
    - McLane, Robert, undated (Box 2:134)
    - McLaughlin, Robert, undated (Box 2:135)
    - Merlati, Sam, 1972 Jul 2 (Box 2:136)
    - Meyerowitz, Lee, 1972 Apr 17 (Box 2:137)
    - Miller, Robert, 1973 Jul 2 (Box 2:138)
    - Millette, Leo H., undated (Box 2:139)
    - Mitchell, John, Jr., 1973 Apr-Aug (Box 2:140)
    - Mueller, Quentin, undated, 1972-1973 (Box 2:141)
    - Munzell, Michael, 1973 Mar 28 (Box 2:142)
    - Ness, Noel, undated (Box 2:143)
    - Nizarre, Frank, undated, 1973 Mar (Box 2:144)
    - Nygren, Edward L., 1972 Dec, May (Box 2:145)
    - O'Brien, Tim, 1973 May-Aug (Box 2:146)
    - Olmstead, Charles W., 1972 May, Aug (Box 2:147)
    - O'Meara, Rick, 1973 Aug 4 (Box 2:148)
    - O'Neill, John T., 1972 Nov-Dec (Box 2:149)
    - Overholser, Stephen, undated, 1971-1973, 1981 (Box 2:150)
    - Paquet, Basil T., undated, 1971-1973 (Box 2:151)
    - Parry, Patrick, undated (Box 2:152)
    - Pelfrey, William, undated, 1972-1973 (Box 2:153)
    - Peterson, James M., undated, 1973 Jan 12 (Box 2:154)
    - Peterson, Vernon, 1973 May 19 (Box 3:155)
    - Pierce, Brad, undated (Box 3:156)
    - Pitts, Oran, 1973 Jan-Feb (Box 3:157)
    - Platke, Stan, undated, 1971-1973 (Box 3:158)
    - Porsche, Don, 1973 Jul-Aug (Box 3:159)
    - Poulter, S.L., undated, 1972-1973 (Box 3:160)
    - Povey, George, 1972 Oct 27 (Box 3:161)
    - Primm, Alex, undated, 1970-1974 (Box 3:162)
    - Purcell, Charles M., undated, 1971-1973 (Box 3:163)
    - Ray, Martin, undated, 1972-1973 (Box 3:164)
    - Receveur, Donald, Jr., undated, 1971-1973 (Box 3:165)
    - Rendleman, Danny L., 1972 NOv 22 (Box 3:166)
    - Reser, Phil, undated, 1971 Dec (Box 3:167)
    - Riesenmy, Robert P., undated (Box 3:168)
    - Rogers, David, 1973 Jul-Aug (Box 3:169)
    - Rotman, Richard E., 1973 Apr, Jun (Box 3:170)
    - Rottmann, Larry, 1973 Jul 26 (Box 3:171)
    - Rudoi, W.H., undated (Box 3:172)
    - Saner, Reginald A., 1973 May, Aug (Box 3:173)
    - Scahill, James Vincent, 1971, 1973 (Box 3:174)
    - Schlosser, Robert L., 1972-1973 (Box 3:175)
    - Schuster, William, 1972 Oct-Nov (Box 3:176)
    - Sessions, David, 1972 Dec 19 (Box 3:177)
    - Setian, Ralph, 1973 Apr 19 (Box 3:178)
    - Shanahan, Michael, 1972 Oct 2 (Box 3:179)
    - Shea, Joseph M., 1973, 1975 (Box 3:180)
    - Shea, Richard H., 1972 Oct-Nov (Box 3:181)
    - Sherman, G., 1974 Jul (Box 3:182)
    - Shibla, Vernon, 1973 Jan- Feb (Box 3:183)
    - Shields, James, 1972-1973 (Box 3:184)
    - Silverman, H., 1972-1973 (Box 3:185)
    - Simon, William J., undated, 1970-1973 (Box 3:186)
    - Singley, William P, 1973 Apr 21 (Box 3:187)
    - Slivka, Sigrid P., 1973 Mar 4 (Box 3:188)
    - Smith, Steven P., 1971-1973 (Box 3:189)
    - Soldati, Joseph A., undated, 1973 Mar, Jul (Box 3:190)
    - Sossaman, Stephen, 1973 Jul (Box 3:191)
    - Stein, Jeffrey, 1972 Oct 21 (Box 3:192)
    - Stern, David, 1972-1973 (Box 3:193)
    - Swift, Paul, 1972 Aug 10 (Box 3:194)
    - Tavela, John, 1972-1973 (Box 3:195)
    - Taylor, Robert G., 1973 Jul 4 (Box 3:196)
    - Tharp, Michael Eugene, 1970, 1972 (Box 3:197)
    - Thorne, Landon, undated, 1972-1973 (Box 3:198)
    - Trail, Ben D., 1973 Jun 5 (Box 3:199)
    - Tripp, Nathaniel, 1973 Jul (Box 3:200)
    - Tyson, K.G., 1973-1974 (Box 3:201)
    - Uhl, Michael, undated, 1971-1973 (Box 3:202)
    - Vaughan, Lantry D., 1972 Oct 6 (Box 3:203)
    - Vigus, William E., undated (Box 3:204)
    - Vinson, Paul A., 1973 Jul (Box 3:205)
    - Warner, Edward R., undated (Box 3:206)
    - Warner, Pate, 1973-1974 (Box 3:207)
    - Watkins, Donald G., undated (Box 3:208)
    - Watts, Carroll, undated (Box 3:209)
    - Weiss, Ritchie, undated (Box 3:210)
    - Weschke, Bernhard P., 1972-1973, 1976 (Box 3:211)
    - Westphall, Victor David, III, undated (Box 3:212)
    - Whitaker, Tommy J., 1972 Nov 6 (Box 3:213)
    - White, Larry, undated (Box 3:214)
    - Whitton, George M., undated (Box 3:215)
    - Willard, Larry, 1972-1974 (Box 3:216)
    - Winslow, John R., Jr., undated, 1971 (Box 3:217)
    - Wolfe, Gerry, 1973-1974 (Box 3:218)
    - Woods, Richard, 1972 Jan 1 (Box 3:219)
    - Yohn, Tim, 1972 Oct 5 (Box 3:220)
    - Younkin, Burrows (Jay), undated, 1971-1973 (Box 3:221)
  - Other Correspondence
    - American Friends Service Committee (AFSC), 1972-1973 (Box 3:222)
    - Cassidy, Tom (FCP Public Relations), 1972 May-Jun (Box 3:223)
    - Committee of Small Magazine Editors and Publishers (COSMEP), undated, 1972-1974 (Box 3:224)
    - Form Letters, undated, 1972-1973 (Box 3:225)
    - General Correspondence, A - C, undated1971-1973 (Box 4:226)
    - General Correspondence, D - G, undated, 1971-1973 (Box 4:227)
    - General Correspondence, H - J, undated1971-1973 (Box 4:228)
    - General Correspondence, K - L, undated, 1971-1973 (Box 4:229)
    - General Correspondence, M - N, undated, 1971-1973 (Box 4:230)
    - General Correspondence, O - R, undated, 1971-1973 (Box 4:231)
    - General Correspondence, S, undated, 1970-1974 (Box 5:232)
    - General Correspondence, T - Z, undated, 2970-1974 (Box 5:233)
    - King, Coretta Scott (Wife of Martin Luther King, Jr.), 1973 Oct 6 (Box 5:234)
    - Mailing Lists, undated, 1972-1973 (Box 5:235)
    - McGovern, George (Senator, Presidential Candidate), 1972 Sep 29 (Box 5:236)
    - New England Small Press Association (NESPA), 1972-1973 (Box 5:237)
    - Newspapers and Periodicals, A - L, undated, 1971-1973 (Box 5:238)
    - Newspapers and Periodicals, M - P, undated, 1971-1973 (Box 5:239)
    - Newspapers and Periodicals, R - Z, undated, 1971-1973 (Box 5:240)
    - Peace Groups, undated, 1972 (Box 5:241)
    - Prisoners, undated, 1972-1973 (Box 6:242)
    - Publishers, undated, 1970-1973 (Box 6:243)
    - Shatan, Chaim F. (Noted Psychologist), 1972 Dec 19 (Box 6:244)
    - TV and Radio, undated, 1972-1973 (Box 6:245)
    - Vietnam Veterans Against the War (VVAW), undated, 1972-1973 (Box 6:246)
- Series II: Writings, 1960-1978
  - Winning Hearts and Minds: War Poems by Vietnam Veterans, edited by Larry Rottmann, Jan Barry and Basil T. Paquet.
    - Submitted works by author
      - Barry, Jan 9 poems, undated, 1971 (Box 7:247)
      - Bobrowsky, Igor 10 poems, undated (Box 7:248)
      - Boyer, James 3 poems, undated (Box 7:249)
      - Brownstein, Stanley, undated (Box 7:250)
      - Buster, Robert D., undated, 1973 (Box 7:251)
      - Casey, Michael, 1971 Dec 27 (Box 7:252)
      - Clinton, L. DeWitt, undated (Box 7:253)
      - Cross, Frank A., Jr., undated, 1969-1973 (Box 7:254)
      - Downey, Mark, undated (Box 7:255)
      - Erhart, William D., undated (Box 7:256)
      - Emeny, Mary, undated (Box 7:257)
      - Fries, Larry, 1971, 1973 (Box 7:258)
      - Hahn, Robert, undated (Box 7:259)
      - Halpern, Sue, undated (Box 7:260)
      - Hasford, Gustav, undated, 1978 Feb 12 (Box 7:261)
      - Hatch, Stephen R., 1970 Jul 17 (Box 7:262)
      - Knaster, Julian, undated, 1971 Jan 13 (Box 7:263)
      - Kohler, Harrison, undated (Box 7:264)
      - Krohn, Herbert, undated, 1966-1971 (Box 7:265)
      - Lytle, John, undated (Box 7:266)
      - McLain, Jack, undated, 1969-1970 (Box 7:267)
      - Paquet, Basil T., undated, 1969 Dec 18 (Box 7:268)
      - Platke, Stan, undated (Box 7:269)
      - Purcell, Charles M., undated, 1970 Nov 24 (Box 7:270)
      - Receveur, Donald Jr., undated (Box 7:271)
      - Rottmann, Larry, undated (Box 7:272)
      - Simon, William J., undated, 1970 Nov 19 (Box 7:273)
      - Smith, Steven P., undated (Box 7:274)
      - Thorne, Landon, 1968-1969 (Box 7:275)
      - Uhl, Michael, 1969 Jan (Box 7:276)
      - Younkin, Burrows, undated (Box 7:277)
    - Publication History
      - Prospectus, undated (Box 8:278)
      - Original TM: Introduction, undated (Box 8:279)
      - Original AM: Table of Contents, undated (Box 8:280)
      - TM: Index, undated (Box 8:281)
      - TM: Author Biographical Information, undated (Box 8:282)
      - TM poems, undated (Box 8:283)
      - Original TM, 1971 (Box 8:284)
      - Original TM, 1971 Fall (Box 8:285)
      - Original TM, undated (Box 8:286)
      - TM [ms corrections], 1972 Spring (Box 8:287)
      - TM [ms corrections w/additions], undated (Box 8:288)
      - TM [photocopy], 1972 Spring (Box 8:289)
      - Original Paste-up [fragile - restricted use], undated (Box 9:290)
      - Paste-up [public use copy], undated (Box 9:291)
      - Promotional Material, undated (Box 9:292)
      - Posters [oversized], undated (Box OS:293)
      - Reviews, 1972-1973 (Box 9:294)
      - Doubleday Author Lecture Series, undated, 1972 Fall (Box 9:295)
      - Public Theater Production, undated, 1972 (Box 9:296)
      - Winning Hearts and Minds: An Experimental Theatre Production of War Poems by Vietnam Veterans, conceived and adapted by Paula Kay Pierce, 1972 (Box 10)
      - Unidentified Notes and Papers, undated (Box 9:297)
  - Free Fire Zone: Short Stories by Vietnam Veterans, edited by Wayne Karlin, Basil T. Paquet, and Larry Rottmann.
    - Submitted works by author
      - Aitken, James, undated (Box 9:298)
      - Bobrowsky, Igor, undated, 1972 Sep 20 (Box 9:299)
      - Cross, Frank A., Jr., 1969, 1971 (Box 9:300)
      - Currer, William J., undated (Box 9:301)
      - Dorris, James R., undated (Box 9:302)
      - Grajewski, Julian, undated, 1972 (Box 11:303)
      - Huddle, David, undated (Box 11:304)
      - Karlin, Wayne, undated (Box 11:305)
      - Little, Loyd, undated (Box 11:306)
      - McCusker, Michael (Mike), 1966-1969 (Box 11:307)
      - Mueller, Quentin, undated, 1970 May 23 (Box 11:308)
      - Paquet, Basil T., undated (Box 11:309)
      - Pelfrey, William, undated, 1970 Nov 21 (Box 11:310)
      - Pitts, Oran, undated (Box 11:311)
      - Rottmann, Larry, undated (Box 11:312-313)
      - Shields, James, 1972 (Box 11:314)
      - Smith, Steven P., undated (Box 11:315)
      - Tavela, John, undated (Box 11:316)
    - Publication History, undated
      - Front matter and notes, undated (Box 11:317)
      - Introduction, undated (Box 11:318)
      - Proof, 1973 (Box 11:319)
      - Bound Proof: ms corrections, undated (Box 12)
      - Bound Proof: ms corrections, undated (Box 13)
      - Final bound proof, undated (Box 14)
      - Promotional Materials, undated (Box 11:320)
      - Reviews, 1973 (Box 11:321)
  - Post Mortem, edited by Basil T. Paquet and Wayne Karlin (unpublished).